<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on The Node</title>
    <link>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on The Node</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Things To Do 2022 Edition</title>
      <link>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/2022-amp-it-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/2022-amp-it-up/</guid>
      <description>System for Continuous Improvement James Clear&amp;rsquo;s book Atomic Habits talks about idea of continuous improvement i.e., 1% better every day. The trick is to form habits.
Focus Sam Altman on How to Successful.
Number 5: Focus is a force multiplier on work. Part of it is to just Say No To Things.
Do the 10k Work Khe Hy on The magic of doing 10k work
Amp It Up! Frank Slootman on Amp It Up!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The China Model</title>
      <link>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/china/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/china/</guid>
      <description>The reason for writing this post is the recent actions by Chinese regulators like banning afterschool tutoring, the ban on video games for kids, Alibaba and Tencent crackdown, etc.
The Chinese model of Capitalism, also referred to Socialist Market Economy is a form of government where the state takes significant interest in managing the economy. This is quite different from India or the US where we practice free markets and minimal state involvement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>11 months at a startup</title>
      <link>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/11months/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/11months/</guid>
      <description>Reflecting on my time at IB, some of the key lessons I learnt (in no particular order)
 Use Jira  Thats it! use jira if you have more than 1 team. Give the team a goal using epics, track all feature rollouts, bugs, contributions per employee, etc.
 Employee Morale and Churn  Startups go through waves. Sometime it feels like you are killing it. Close a new customer, launch a new product, land a great hire, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Focus</title>
      <link>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/focus/</guid>
      <description>Sam Altman in his How To Be Successful had the following to say about focus
6. Focus Focus is a force multiplier on work. Almost everyone I’ve ever met would be well-served by spending more time thinking about what to focus on. It is much more important to work on the right thing than it is to work many hours. Most people waste most of their time on stuff that doesn’t matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyper and In-Memory Databases</title>
      <link>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/hyper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/hyper/</guid>
      <description>AWS has made it easy to get the latest and greatest hardware. You can easily get machines O(TB) of DRAM for a few dollars per hour. r5.16x large instance for example has the following specs:
r5.16xlarge	64vCPU	256ECU	512 GiB	EBS Only	$4.032 per Hour TPC-H benchmark is a standard dataset is a popular OLAP benchmark. Scale factor 1000 of TPC-H benchmark generates 1TB of data which after removing ununsed columns and dictionary compression come to nearly 280GB of data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coronavirus and Europe - Storm Beneath the Calm</title>
      <link>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/coronavirus-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/coronavirus-economy/</guid>
      <description>Over the years, I have had the good fortune of travelling to many countries - one of which is Italy. Italy is a beautiful country with many historic cities - Rome, Vatican, Florence, Milan, etc. The travel and tourism industry is the largest industry in Italy - accounting for ~13% of Italy&amp;rsquo;s GDP.
The coronavirus pandemic has torpedoed the travel industry. Large parts of Italy are on lock down after being hit by the biggest outbreak of COVID-19.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Credit reports and security in the offline world</title>
      <link>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/credit-report-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 15:09:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/credit-report-security/</guid>
      <description>Credit score is a number almost every individual in the country cares about. Your credit score determines if you can get a particular credit card, how much interest you pay on a loan, etc. Credit scores are calculated based on your credit report, an exhaustive account of all your past dealings with financial entities.
There are 3 major credit reporting agencies in the US: Equifax, TransUnion and Experian. The law requires each of these nationwide credit reporting companies to provide you with a free copy of your credit report, at your request, once every 12 months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing the 2016 elections</title>
      <link>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/2016-elections/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/2016-elections/</guid>
      <description>Elections are a treat for data enthusiasts. This elections, even more so ! Every single poll in the US predicted a landslide for Hillary Clinton. Below is an infographic from the New York Times:
The chances of Trump winning Presidency before results started coming out was around 15% ! Everyone got it wrong and in the end he won 306 seats. Being curious, I download the data from AP and turned on my Jupyter notebook.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
