<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on The Node</title>
    <link>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on The Node</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>When China Learns - Auto Edition</title>
      <link>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/when-china-learns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/when-china-learns/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;China has long been a manufacturing powerhouse, excelling in industries from electronics to textiles. Its ability to produce goods at scale and lower costs has fueled its dominance. However, in industries requiring advanced technology and strong brand recognition, China has historically lagged behind. That is now changing—fast.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;rise-of-chinese-automakers&#34;&gt;Rise of Chinese Automakers&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The automotive industry is a prime example of rise of China. In 2019, none of the top 10 global automakers were Chinese. Despite being the world&amp;rsquo;s largest automotive market, Chinese car manufacturers struggled with quality, technology, and brand perception compared to established international brands.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Netflix thesis</title>
      <link>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/netflix-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/netflix-thesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First mover advantage.&lt;/strong&gt; The problem Netflix solves for consumers is entertainment. Netflix solves this problem for a large base - 200m+. While competing services will come up, customer acquisition will be challenging. Young folks who have had Netflix and Amazon Prime Video for years will not want to pay for another third service. They might subscribe to HBO Max to watch one show/movie like Dune and cancel after watching. Unless these new services pump out content at the rate of Netflix, they will not get traction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Things To Do 2022 Edition</title>
      <link>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/2022-amp-it-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/2022-amp-it-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;system-for-continuous-improvement&#34;&gt;System for Continuous Improvement&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;James Clear&amp;rsquo;s book &lt;a href=&#34;https://jamesclear.com/atomic-habits&#34;&gt;Atomic Habits&lt;/a&gt; talks about idea of continuous improvement i.e., 1% better every day. The trick is to form habits.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;focus&#34;&gt;Focus&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sam Altman on &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.samaltman.com/how-to-be-successful&#34;&gt;How to Successful&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Number 5: Focus is a force multiplier on work. Part of it is to just Say No To Things.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;do-the-10k-work&#34;&gt;Do the 10k Work&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Khe Hy on &lt;a href=&#34;https://radreads.co/10k-work/&#34;&gt;The magic of doing 10k work&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;amp-it-up&#34;&gt;Amp It Up!&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Frank Slootman on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/amp-up-frank-slootman/&#34;&gt;Amp It Up!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The China Model</title>
      <link>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/china/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/china/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The reason for writing this post is the recent actions by Chinese regulators like banning afterschool tutoring, the ban on video games for kids, Alibaba and Tencent crackdown, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Chinese model of Capitalism, also referred to Socialist Market Economy is a form of government where the state takes significant interest in managing the&#xA;economy. This is quite different from India or the US where we practice free markets and minimal state involvement. If we ignore the politics, it is undeniable that&#xA;the Chinese model has produced dramatically better outcomes for its people compared to India/US.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>11 months at a startup</title>
      <link>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/11months/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/11months/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on my time at IB, some of the key lessons I learnt (in no particular order)&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Use Jira&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Thats it! use jira if you have more than 1 team. Give the team a goal using epics, track all feature rollouts, bugs, contributions per employee, etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Employee Morale and Churn&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Startups go through waves. Sometime it feels like you are killing it.&#xA;Close a new customer, launch a new product, land a great hire, etc. Sometimes it feels like outright dumpster fire.&#xA;Inevitably, this leads to some employees feeling low and will quit. IB is no different, however one thing&#xA;that helps a lot is if the core team, especially eng is stable. IB has all key managers stay through these cycles for many years and plan to stay for many more.&#xA;This creates stability as foot soldiers churn is not as determinental as commander churn.&#xA;An orthongal point is you need to identify and fire useless people and more importantly detractors fast.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Focus</title>
      <link>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/focus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sam Altman in his &lt;code&gt;How To Be Successful&lt;/code&gt; had the following to say about focus&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;background-color:#fff;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;6. Focus&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Focus is a force multiplier on work.&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Almost everyone I’ve ever met would be well-served by spending more time thinking about what to focus on. It is much more important to work on the right thing than it is to work many hours. Most people waste most of their time on stuff that doesn’t matter.&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Once you have figured out what to do, be unstoppable about getting your small handful of priorities accomplished quickly. I have yet to meet a slow-moving person who is very successful.&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Focus is an incredible force. I have found many times that working with full focus for a day&#xA;gets more work done than without focus work for a week. Despite the huge benefits, maintaing focus is hard!&#xA;When your work is on the computer, it is hard not to want to peep into Twitter to see what is happening or open&#xA;Youtube to checkout a few videos.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hyper and In-Memory Databases</title>
      <link>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/hyper/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/hyper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AWS has made it easy to get the latest and greatest hardware. You can easily get machines O(TB) of DRAM for a few dollars per hour. r5.16x large instance for example has the following specs:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; style=&#34;background-color:#fff;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;display:flex;&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;r5.16xlarge&#x9;64vCPU&#x9;256ECU&#x9;512 GiB&#x9;EBS Only&#x9;$4.032 per Hour&#xA;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;TPC-H benchmark is a standard dataset is a popular OLAP benchmark. Scale factor 1000 of TPC-H benchmark generates 1TB of data which after removing ununsed columns and dictionary compression come to nearly 280GB of data. This dataset has 6 billion rows !&#xA;This dataset can easily be operated on using an in-memory database &amp;mdash; one of the best in-memory databases is Hyper. Hyper can operate at memory-bandwidth speed (~150GBps on a Xeon today).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coronavirus and Europe - Storm Beneath the Calm</title>
      <link>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/coronavirus-economy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/coronavirus-economy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/img/falling-dominoes.webp&#34; alt=&#34;Falling Dominoes&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Over the years, I have had the good fortune of travelling to many countries - one of which is Italy. Italy is a beautiful country with many historic cities - Rome, Vatican, Florence, Milan, etc. The travel and tourism industry is the largest industry in Italy - accounting for ~13% of Italy&amp;rsquo;s GDP.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The coronavirus pandemic has torpedoed the travel industry. Large parts of Italy are on lock down after being hit by the biggest outbreak of COVID-19. All famous tourist attractions are closed for now and not likely to open before mid-May. People plan for travel many months in advance &amp;mdash; even if things do open there is likely going to significantly lower level for a few months. So, in effect the tourism industry is going at close to 0 revenue until August. The problem is tourism is seasonal. Looking at air traffic in Europe:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Credit reports and security in the offline world</title>
      <link>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/credit-report-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 15:09:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/credit-report-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Credit score is a number almost every individual in the country cares about. Your credit score determines if you can get a particular credit card, how much interest you pay on a loan, etc.  Credit scores are calculated based on your credit report, an exhaustive account of all your past dealings with financial entities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are 3 major credit reporting agencies in the US: Equifax, TransUnion and Experian. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.consumer.ftc.gov/articles/0155-free-credit-reports&#34;&gt;law&lt;/a&gt; requires each of these nationwide credit reporting companies to provide you with a free copy of your credit report, at your request, once every 12 months. Given the private nature of this information, you would assume they have mechanisms to let you access this information securely. TransUnion and Experian allow you access it online or mail, but for Equifax says the only way to get your report is via snail mail. What! why would anyone in 2017 send credit reports by mail; it insecure, can easily end up get lost / misplaced / in the hands of an identity thief. Below are two pages from an Equifax credit report I accidently ended up recieving.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing the 2016 elections</title>
      <link>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/2016-elections/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/2016-elections/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Elections are a treat for data enthusiasts. This elections, even more so ! Every single poll in the US predicted a landslide for Hillary Clinton. Below is an infographic from the New York Times:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/img/nyt-infographic.png&#34; alt=&#34;NYT Infographic&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The chances of Trump winning Presidency before results started coming out was around 15% ! Everyone got it wrong and in the end he won 306 seats. Being curious, I download the data from AP and turned on my Jupyter notebook. The truth is this could have been a lot worse!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
