<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on The Node</title>
    <link>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on The Node</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 15:09:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Credit reports and security in the offline world</title>
      <link>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/credit-report-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 15:09:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/credit-report-security/</guid>
      <description>Credit score is a number almost every individual in the country cares about. Your credit score determines if you can get a particular credit card, how much interest you pay on a loan, etc. Credit scores are calculated based on your credit report, an exhaustive account of all your past dealings with financial entities.
There are 3 major credit reporting agencies in the US: Equifax, TransUnion and Experian. The law requires each of these nationwide credit reporting companies to provide you with a free copy of your credit report, at your request, once every 12 months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing the 2016 elections</title>
      <link>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/2016-elections/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2017 14:27:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.anilshanbhag.in/posts/2016-elections/</guid>
      <description>Elections are a treat for data enthusiasts. This elections, even more so ! Every single poll in the US predicted a landslide for Hillary Clinton. Below is an infographic from the New York Times:
The chances of Trump winning Presidency before results started coming out was around 15% ! Everyone got it wrong and in the end he won 306 seats. Being curious, I download the data from AP and turned on my Jupyter notebook.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>